# Tannus Esquerdo

# Front-end Developer

+1 (647) 767-9504 | tannusewrton@gmail.com | Toronto, CA

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Frontend-focused web developer with a passion for design. During my 4+ years in website development field, I have had the opportunity to strengthen my knowledge of front-end languages and frameworks, including Angular, Ionic, React, Ruby on Rails and countless other frontend and backend frameworks and tools, but I spend most of my time dealing with HTML, Javascript and CSS/SCSS. I'm self-motivated so I can work alone but also have great interpersonal skills that make it easy to work with a team both inside and outside the company.

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

Front End	CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, React, Gatsby, React Native, Styled Components, Angular, Ionic, Webpack, SCSS, LESS, PHP, Wordpress
Back End	Ruby, Rails,Node.JS, PHP, APIs, Java
Data Stores	MySQL, MongoDB
Operating Systems	Ubuntu, Mac OS

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER | AIRSELLS Inc. | Charlottetown, PE - Remote

OUT 2019 - FEB 2021

Airsells connects people with flat fee local services nearby. The community is powered by local businesses, freelancers and experts, who provide their clients with a unique opportunity to book their services instantly.

- Principal front-end developer that build from scratch a Headless CMS: Wordpress + React
- Assisted in the development of plugins for WordPress to connect the Headless CMS with React.
- <u>Technologies</u>: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Native, Styled Components, CSS/SCSS, Javascript, PHP, Wordpress, Git, Scrum

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER | DITO | Belo Horizonte, Brazil

JUL 2015 – SET 2019

Member of a SaaS Startup whose role is to provide a CRM tool for marketing teams. The platform allows Marketing teams the autonomy to know their consumers in depth from profile data, browsing behavior and purchase history in e-commerce and physical stores.

- Executed and contributed to full-stack web development projects, with an emphasis on front end features, browser manipulation, and cross-browser compatibility.
- Refactor the existing code, implement new features and improving the platform performance

- Build new systems to help in metrics analytics and customer success support
- Work directly with clients (internal and external) to resolve issues with the Company's integration of software products and services
- Assisted in the development of plugins for WordPress and Magento
- <u>Technologies</u>: HTML5, CSS/SCSS, Javascript, AngularJS, CoffeeScript, PHP, Ruby on Rails, Ionic, Vuejs, React, Git, Scrum

#### INTERN FRONT-END DEVELOPER | DITO | Belo Horizonte, Brazil

NOV 2014 – JUL 2015

Development of TIM beta project of 7 million users, a cell phone plan designed for youngsters who have intense use of data and social networks to gain points. The product recognizes the most important clients offering them exclusive discounts and benefits.

- Designed and coded application in an agile environment utilizing a test-driven development approach
- Maintained, refactor the existing code and implement new features
- Assisted in the development of products for internal use
- Created HTML email templates and newsletters for email marketing campaigns
- Converts PSDs into hand-coded HTML/CSS
- <u>Technologies</u>: HTML5, CSS/SCSS, Javascript, Backbone.js, Ruby on Rails, Git, Scrum

# **EDUCATION**

Software Engineering Technology   Centennial College, Toronto, Canada	MAY 2022 - PRES
Computer Science   Pitágoras College   Belo Horizonte, Brazil	JAN 2015 – DROP
FullStack Master Class   Juno College   Toronto, Canada	OCT 2019 – DEZ 2019
GRAPHIC DESIGN   Senai/Cecoteg   Belo Horizonte, Brazil	JAN 2010 – JUN 2011

# **PROFILES**

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/tannusesquerdo
Twitter: twitter.com/tannusesquerdo
Github: github.com/tannusesquerdo